Linux Terminal Setup
On Google play  store and download
Termux Application
Install the application
Termux is a Linux environment application
Every Linux command can be run and
executed on the termux application.
After installation, start the application
to see this black environment
(N.B: The keyboard used is known as
hackers keyboard which can be found
on google play store.)
Update termux using 'pkg update'
'pkg' stands for package
This updates the application to
the latest version
Whenever a package is installing
or updating, the terminal asks for
permission to continue; remember to always
select a yes by typing 'y'
This will allow the application package to
install or update completely
Some packages take time to install,
while others are faster
Try to wait patiently for the packages
to be fully installed or updated.
Go to www.google.com in your browser
search for 'oh-my-termux'
and go to this github repository
(this current page)
Highlight and copy the URL
under Requirement
Go back to your termux terminal
and paste the URL
(Long-press on your screen to paste)
Return to your browser,
highlight and copy the URL
under Installation
Go back to the your termux terminal
and paste the coipied URL
and press 'enter'
After the cloning is completed,
allow termux to access you android device
You will need to restart your android
device to complete your installations
Type 'exit' to quit the application
Restart your termux application
Notice the new background of your terminal
Install new packages using the command
'pkg install'
First two packages you will install are
'unzip' and 'git'
The first git command used in this tutorial
is 'git config' used with these flags
'--global username' and '--global email'
This command is used to add your
github username and password to your
local git repository on your android device
(You will learn of git and github in
later tutorial videos)
N.B: You will need to create a
github account in order to set your
username and email
To check the version of git you have,
the flag '--version'