Linux Commands
PWD means Present Working Directory
It shows the current directory you're in
The 'ping' command
Is used to check for internet connectivity
ping + 'website URL'
The following response indicates
That you have internet connectivity
Use CTRL+C to stop the response
One of the most usefull command is
'ls' which means list
It lists out the contents of a directory
ls -a
lists out all hidden directories
(hidden files have a dot at the beginning)
ls -l
lists out details about each item
in the directory
ls -al
lists out both hidden and unhidden files
including all their details
The next command is
cd
which stands for Change Directory
cd + 'directory path'
'cd storage' changes directory to
the  /storage directory
To return back to your
previous directory, type
cd ..
you can cd into your default storage
on your android device
located in the /storage/shared directory
To return to the home directory
type cd ../..
use the up arrow key on your keyboard
to go to your previous codes
cd ~ (tild symbol)
also returns to the home directory
cd - (hyphen symbol)
displays your current path
Type 'ls'
to list out all the contents of /shared
directory which is also the
internal storage of your android device
Compare the listed content with
the actual contents in your file manager
to see that they are the same files
This means that you can access
your file manager from your
termux terminal
You can list out the contents of
the home directory from your
current directory using 'ls ~'
mkdir is the command for
making a new directory
mkdir + 'new directory'
Go to your file manager
to see the new folder you created
Open the new folder and create
another new folder manually
Next, check your termux terminal
and cd into the directory created on termux
type 'ls' to see the new folder you created
from your file manager
(Note: A folder is called a directory
in linux)
Return to the home directory
Try to make a sub directory
inside the sub directory of the
new directory you previously created
An error is encountered because
a sub-directory cannot be created without
a parent directory
mkdir -p (parent flag)
creates the parent directories and
the sub directories
List out the contents of the sub-directory
you just created to view your new
sub-directory
From the home directory, create a new
directory inside your device storage
create it inside the folder that was
previously created
Next, open your file manager
to see the new folder you just created
From the home directory, you'll create
a hidden folder inside your device
internal storage
N.B: You can use the tab key to
autocomplete the names of directories
Adding a dot before a directory makes
it to become a hidden directory
Check your file manager to see
the hidden directory created
N.B: If you can't view the hidden folders,
go to the options that shows hidden folders
The 'touch' command is used to
create new files
Use the 'ls' command to view the new file
Create a new file in your internal storage
Go to your file manager to see the new file
Also create a new hidden file also in your
internal storage
Remember to add a dot to hide a file
rm (remove) is used to delete a file
rm + 'path of file to delete'
Delete the last hidden file created in
your internal storage
Check your file manager to see that the
file is deleted
rm cannot delete a directory but
will result in an error
Instead a recursive flag is used after 'rm'
rm -R 'path to directory'
Check your file manager to confirm
that the folders are successfully deleted
Also confirm on your terminal using 'ls'
Clear command clears the terminal
cp is the command to copy a file
cp -r is used to copy a directory
mv is the command to move a file