Neovim and Emmet Tutorial
Create a directory named 'sites'
then create a sub-directory inside 'sites'
and name it 'sample1'.
Change directory from home [~] to
'sites/sample1' directory
Open a new file in neovim named 'file.txt'
Your new file opens up in normal mode
which you will be unable to edit your file
press "i" to go to insert mode
You can type anything of choice
into your file.
Add as many lines to the file as you can
Exit the insert mode using the ESC key
VISUAL MODE is where highlighting words
and lines is possible. To switch to
visual mode, press the letter "v"
use your arrow keys to highlight the words
or lines that you want to copy or cut
This is the same with 'click and drag'
on PCs or on other applications
You can use the ESC key to exit from
visual mode.
Then use your arrow keys to place your
cursor on the word you want to highlight
and press "v", then use your arrows
to select the full word or line.
Capital letter "V" is used  to select
line after line, not words.
Place your cursor on the line you wish to
highlight and press your capital "V"
use your arrow keys to select more lines
you want to highlight
Use the ESC key to deselect
Select another set of lines
and press letter "d" to cut or delete.
You are now in normal mode
Scroll(with arrows) to your last line and
press letter "p" to paste.
Remember you are still in
normal mode.
There is another letter used to
enter INSERT MODE other than letters
"i" and "a".
Press capital "O" to edit the line
directly before the pasted content
Scroll back up and paste again where you
cut from.
In neovim, the command to copy
is known as yanking.
Scroll to a line and place your cursor on a
word you want to copy, use "v" to
highlight them and then
Press letter "y" to yank or copy
Move to the end of the line and paste
using the letter "p".
Practice by pasting in differnt places
You can create a new file from your
current file.
Using the command :!touch 'nameofFile'
You can also create a new directory from
your current file, using this command
:!mkdir 'NameOfDirectory
To view your files and directories
from your present file,
press CTRL + O.
You will see the NERDTreeToggle
To switch between the two
windows(NerdTree and the editor),
press CTRL + W.
Save your changes using :!w
Use capital letter "R" to refresh
the nerd tree.
Scroll to the new file you created in your
nerd tree and press 'enter' to open
Press CTRL + O to close the NerdTree
Enter insert mode using "i"
Edit the file
and save it
Open the NerdTree again using ctrl+O
Create a new html file
using  " :!touch nameof file.html "
Refresh the NerdTree to see the new file
press the letter "m" to open
the NerdTree Menu
Press "m" again to exit and press enter
to open your html file.
Press ctrl+O to close the NerdTree
In insert mode, type "html:5~"
type "html:5" followed by 2 commas(,,)
In Emmet, double commas are used to
execute or complete tags in html.
So the complete HTML boiler-plate is
written out for you to make things easier.
Edit the title
To create a div and another div inside,
type "div>div" followed by double commas
To create a heading tag,
type "h1" followed by double commas
Type your heading in between the opening
and closing tag
Go to a new line and type "p" followed by
2 commas. You now have a paragraph tag
Edit your paragraph between the tags
Emmet allows you to type shrinked commands
and then the double comma's expand those
commands into full parent and child tags.
The dot represents a div with a class while
the # represents a div with an id
The > sign is to create a child tag while
the + sign is to create a sibling tag and
the ^ symbol is to create a parent-sibling
tag.
Remember to use double commas to execute
You can see the expanded code now
Type in anything within your div tags
ESC and save your page and quit using this
command :wq
Do an 'ls' to list out the contents of your
PWD (present working directory)
Copy your html file to ~/storage/shared/
Go to your file manager and look for
the html file you just created and copied.
When you have found it, open it
It will open up in a browser and
display all you wrote in your html file.
Go back to your termux terminal and exit.