Neovim- Part 1
In this tuturial, we will learn how to use
the text editor, neovim
Firstly, you will have to update your
application
After updating, you will install the
text editor
pkg install neovim nodejs yarn
To install multiple packages(applications),
you can type them all after 'pkg install'
'nodejs' is a package that will be
needed when writing javascript codes
'yarn' is a package manager for your code
All these packages will be installed
all at once.
Next, we will create a directory
named 'nvim' in a .config directory
Recall that 'mkdir' is the command
for creating new directories and the flag
-p is for creating a parent directory
This means that /.config/ is the parent
directory, while /nvim/ is the
sub directory.
We will do a 'git clone' command next
which will clone all the contents of the
repository into our android device
We are cloning the 'env.git' file,
which means the file will be copied
from themobileprof's repository to
our file manager on our android device
Then copy the contents of the cloned file
to the nvim directory you created earlier
Be careful to replicate the exact commands
on the screen and take note of
the spacing between the directory you're
copying from and to the one you're
copying to
Next, go to your browser and search for
'vim-plug' on google.
Go to the github repository as seen
on this video.
Scroll down to neovim and under unix/linux
Highlight and copy the
URL as seen
Be careful to highlight every word and
every letter
Paste the URL in your termux terminal
After the successful installation,
you can open the neovim text editor
with the command 'nvim'
This is the neovim environment
Install the basic neovim plugin using the
:PlugInstall command
N.B: In Neovim, the colon mark preceeds
every command.
After the installation is completed,
you'll have to quit the installation page
The command, ":q" is used to quit
You can now edit on your neovim and quit
but the command to quit after editing,
without saving, is different from ":q"
The command to force quit is ":q!"
Go back to neovim editor to continue
more plugin installations
The next plugin to be installed is known as
CoC(Conquer of Completion). It is a
plugin that makes your neovim to be as
a code editor on a computer.
The command to install is ":CocInstall"
followed by other necessary extensions
such as coc-html, coc-css
coc-emmet, coc-git, coc-json
coc-phpls, coc-tsserver
It will a little time for all these
installations to be completed.
This plugin is useful for fast instant
increment code completion;
It is also reliable, features full LSP
(Language Server Protocol) support.
It makes neovim to be configured like
VSCode and the extensions will work
just like in VSCode.
Quit neovim and restart
To start editing a new file with neovim,
type the name of the file after 'nvim'
That is:  nvim 'NameofFile'
You will discover that you are unable to
edit or type anything. This is because you
are not yet in INSERT MODE.
Currently this is the NORMAL MODE where
you will unable to edit you can only
copy and paste here
To switch from one mode to another
press the ESC key on your hackers keyboard
To enter into INSERT MODE, just type
the letter "i"
Now you can be able to type into
the editor
You can use your arrow keys to navigate
between words and letters
within your editor
Use the ESC key to exit the insert mode
An alternative to the arrow keys are the
letters "k", "j", "h" and "l"
"k" is for scrolling upwards,
"j" is for downward scrolling
"h" is for moving to the left
"l" is for moving to the right
(Note that all these navigation can only
be done when in normal mode.)
Apart from using the  letter "i" to enter
insert mode, letter "a" can also be used
But notice that "i" places the cursor
behind the character,
while "a" places the cursor in front
of the character.
Capital letter "A" puts the cursor at the
beginning of the line, while
capital letter "I" places the cursor at
the end of the line.
To jump between words, that is,
from word to word towards the right,
for easier and faster navigation,
the letter "w" is used
while the letter "b" is used to jump
backwards, from right to left.
The use of letter "e" is similar to that of
"w", but "e" jumps to the end of a word
while "w" jumps to the beginning of a word
To jump to another line, you can
type the line number using this command
: + line number
[Try to practice these commands
in different possible ways]
To jump backwards to the beginning of a
line from your current cursor position,
the number "0" is used
while the character "$" is used to jump
the end of the line.
Capital letter "G" is used to jump to the
end of your document,
while letter "g" is used to jump to the
beginning of the document.
Remember all these commands apply
only in NORMAL MODE.
To delete just a single character or
a letter in a line,
the letter "x" is used
To use the quit command, be sure you are
in the normal mode. Press the ESC key if
you are not sure
If you try to quit without saving your
changes,  you will see an error message
The command to save is ":w"
which means to write in
your internal storage
You can now successfully quit after saving
Use your UP arrow key to display your
previous command and press ENTER
We will make some changes to this
file and then try to force quit
Type  "a" to enter into insert mode
[You can probably choose to type
whatever you prefer]
Make sure to exit normal mode before
typing the quit command
The error is because we did not
save changes before trying to quit.
Now try the fore quit command which is
:q!
Display the previous command
using your up arrow and press enter
You will discover that all the
previous changes made were gone
because we did not save and
we forcefully quit.
Now still make new changes to the document
Save changes and quit using the command
:wq
This ends this tutorial